henkel.com 2015-06-10

# Privacy Statement

**1\. General**  

Henkel AG & Co. KGaA, hereinafter referred to as Henkel, respects the privacy of each person who visits our website. Now we would like to inform you of the type of data collected by Henkel and how they are used. You will also learn how you can check the accuracy of this information and arrange for the deletion of these data by Henkel. Data are collected, processed and used in conformity with the data protection regulations of the country in which the responsible data processing department is located. We take any action required to ensure compliance.  

This Privacy Statement does not apply to websites accessible from hyperlinks on Henkel websites.

 **2\. Collection, use and processing of personal data**  

We collect data relating to a specific person for processing and usage purposes only, if you voluntarily decide to enter the data or expressly give your consent thereto. By doing so, you accept the following terms of use.  

When visiting our website, certain data are automatically stored on our servers for the purpose of system administration or for statistical or backup purposes. These data comprise the name of your Internet service provider, in some cases your IP address, the version of your browser software, the operating system of the computer used to access our website, the website you are using to visit us, the websites that you visit while you are with us and, if applicable, any search terms you have been using to find our website. Depending on the circumstances, such data may allow that conclusions be drawn about certain visitors to the website. However, no person-related data are used in this context. Such data are used solely after having been rendered anonymously. If Henkel transfers data to an external service-provider, technical and organizational measures will be taken which guarantee that their transmission occurs in conformity with the statutory data protection regulations.

If you voluntarily supply us with personal-related data, we shall not use, process or transfer these data beyond the limits permitted by statute or defined by yourself in your declaration of consent. Furthermore, we will transfer your data only, if we are obliged to do so by official or court orders.

Any changes to this Privacy Statement will be published on this page. This enables you to inform yourself at any time about which data we are storing and how we collect and use such data.

 **3\. Security**  

Henkel will store your data safely and, therefore, take all precautionary measures to protect your data against loss, abuse or changes. Contractual partners of Henkel who have access to your data in order to provide services to you on behalf of Henkel are contractually obliged to keep such information in confidence and may not use these data for any other purpose. In some cases, it will be necessary that we transfer your inquiries to affiliated companies of Henkel. Also in these cases your data will be treated confidential.

 **4\. Person-related Data of Children**  

Henkel does not wish to collect data on children below the age of 14 years. Where necessary, Henkel will expressly draw the children's attention in an appropriate place to the fact that they shall not send any person-related information to Henkel. Should parents or other legal guardians discover that the children under their supervision have made person-related data available to Henkel, we request that they contact us at the address below (see 6. below), if these data shall be deleted. We shall then arrange for the deletion of these data without delay.  

 **6\. Web Tracking**  

This website collects and stores data for marketing and optimization purposes by using a technology of Webtrekk GmbH. This data can be used to create pseudonymized user profiles. Cookies might be set.  

Without an explicit agreement by our users the data collected with the Webtrekk technologies is not used to identify a visitor personally and is not aggregated with any other personal data about the holder of the pseudonym.  

You can refuse the data collection and storage by Webtrekk by clicking on the link below:

To exclude the Webtrekk web controlling on this website an opt-out cookie is set by www.henkel.com. This exclusion is valid for 5 years or until you delete the cookie. The cookie is set for the named domain, per browser and computer. Therefore, if you visit our website visit at home and work or with different browsers, you need to refuse data storage with every device or browser.  

Please find further information about the web tracking in the privacy policy of our provider: [Webtrekk Privacy Policy](http://www.webtrekk.com/en/index/dataprivacy.html) 

 **7\. Your Wishes and Queries / Data Protection Officer**

Stored data will be deleted by Henkel upon expiration of the statutory or contractual filing period or if Henkel no longer requires the same. At any time, you may, of course, ask for the deletion of your data. You are also entitled at any time to revoke your consent to the use or processing of your person-related data with future effect. In these cases, or if you have any other wishes in connection with your person-related data, please send an e-mail or a letter to our data protection officer, Mr. Frank Liebich, Henkelstrasse 67, D 40191 Düsseldorf, Germany (E-Mail: Datenschutz@henkel.com). Please also contact us this way, if you would like to know whether we have collected data about you and, if so, which data. We shall endeavor to comply with your wish immediately.

 **8\. Public Register of Processing**  

The Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) stipulates in § 4 g that the data protection officer shall make the following data available to anyone in a suitable manner in accordance with § 4 e:

 **(1) Name of the responsible entity:** Henkel AG & Co. KGaA

 **(2) Personally liable partner / Management Board:** Henkel Management AG

  * Kasper Rorsted (Chairman)
  * Carsten Knobel
  * Jan-Dirk Auris
  * Hans Van Bylen
  * Bruno Piacenza
  * Kathrin Menges

Corporate Senior Vice President Data Processing: Joachim Jaeckle

 **(3) Address of the responsible entity:** 40191 Düsseldorf, Germany

 **(4) Intended purpose of data collection, processing or use:**

  * The object of the corporation is the manufacture and distribution of chemical products of all kinds, especially detergents, cleaning agents and care products, chemical raw materials, adhesives and industrial chemicals;
  * personal care products and cosmetics, pharmaceutical products;
  * food stuffs, packaging materials
  * technical equipments and installations
  * the acquisition and management of real estate including land for agriculture and forestry use.

The corporation may acquire domestic and foreign companies of all kinds or participate in them and do any business and action which is conducive to the objects of the corporation.  

 **(5) Description of the groups of persons affected and the respective data or data categories** :

Data relating to customers, employees, pensioners, employees of affiliated companies, employees of external companies (subcontractors), leasing personnel, job applicants, external inventors or heirs, respectively, suppliers and service-providers, external customers, consumers, volunteers in consumer tests, visitors to the corporations site, investors as well as financial analysts and shareholders - insofar as necessary for fulfilling the purposes specified under 7. (4).  

 **(6) Recipients or categories of recipients to whom the data may be disclosed notified:**  

Public authorities, health insurance funds and employers' liability association in the event of the presence of the relevant legal regulations, external contractors in accordance with §11 BDSG, external service-providers, Henkel pensioners' association, affiliated companies and internal departments for fulfilling the purposes specified in 7. (4).  

 **(7) Regular periods for deletion of the data:  **

The legislators have issued a wide range of storage duties and periods of storage. The data are deleted as a matter of routine after the expiration of these periods. Data not affected by such provisions are deleted if the purposes specified in 7. (4) have ceased to exist.  

 **(8) Planned data transfer to third countries:**  

As part of a global HR information system, the personnel data are to be made available to selected management executives in third countries. Corresponding data protection agreements in accordance with EU standard will be contractually agreed upon with the respective companies.

 **9\. Use of Social Media Plug-ins**

Plug-ins (“plug-ins”) of the social media networks facebook.com and Twitter may be embedded in our web pages. The associated services are provided by the companies Facebook Inc. and Twitter Inc. respectively (“providers”).  

Facebook is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook"). For an overview of the Facebook plug-ins and their appearance, go to: <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins>

Twitter is operated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. For an overview of the Twitter buttons and their appearance, go to: <https://twitter.com/about/resources/buttons>[ ](https://twitter.com/about/resources/buttons)

To increase the protection afforded to your data when you visit our web pages, these plug-ins are implemented as “2-click buttons.” This form of integration ensures that, when accessing a page from within our website containing such plug-ins, you are not automatically connected to the providers’ servers. Only if you activate the plug-ins, thus issuing a permission for data transmission, will the browser create a direct link to the providers’ servers. The content of the various plug-ins is then transmitted by the provider concerned directly to your browser and then displayed on your screen. 

The plug-in tells the provider which of our website pages you have accessed. If, while viewing our website, you are logged into your Facebook or Twitter user account, the provider is able to collate your interest, i.e. the information you are accessing, with your user account. On making use of any of the plug-in functions (e.g. clicking the “Like” button, leaving a comment), this information too will be transmitted by the browser directly to the provider for retention.  

Further information on the collection and use of data by Facebook or Twitter and on the rights and possibilities available to you for protecting your privacy in these circumstances can be found in the providers’ data protection/privacy advisories:  

Data protection/privacy advisory issued by Facebook: [http://www.facebook.com/policy.php ](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)

Data protection/privacy advisory issued by Twitter: [https://twitter.com/privacy ](https://twitter.com/privacy)  

To avoid allowing Facebook or Twitter to link your visit of our website to your user account with these providers, you will need to log-off the respective user account prior to accessing our web pages.
